<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">Based Cooking</title>
<subtitle type="text">blog</subtitle>
<updated>2021-03-22T19:39:28Z</updated>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://based.cooking/"/>
<id>https://based.cooking/atom.xml</id>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://based.cooking//atom.xml"/>
<entry>
<title type="text">Crab salad</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://based.cooking/crab-salad.html"/>
<id>https://based.cooking/crab-salad.html</id>
<published>2021-03-22T19:14:25Z</published>
<updated>2021-03-22T19:14:25Z</updated>
<author><name>mrtree4</name></author>
<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Crab salad</h1>

<h2>Ingredients</h2>

<ul>
<li>Сrab meat</li>
<li>Egg</li>
<li>Rice</li>
<li>Corn</li>
<li>Cucumber</li>
<li>Carrot</li>
<li>Onion</li>
<li>Mayonnaise</li>
</ul>


<h2>Directions</h2>

<ol>
<li>Chop crab meat and all other ingredients</li>
<li>Combine and mix all ingredients</li>
<li>Add mayonnaise</li>
<li>Chill before serving</li>
</ol>


<h2>Contribution</h2>

<p>Anonymous</p>

<p>;tags: salad russian</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title type="text">Pasta Alla Norma</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://based.cooking/pasta-alla-norma.html"/>
<id>https://based.cooking/pasta-alla-norma.html</id>
<published>2021-03-22T16:13:30Z</published>
<updated>2021-03-22T16:13:30Z</updated>
<author><name>kentishh</name></author>
<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Pasta Alla Norma</h1>

<p>A delicious Sicilian pasta dish, with Aubergines in a tomato sauce topped with fresh basil.</p>

<ul>
<li>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min</li>
<li>🍳 Cook time: 40 min</li>
<li>🍽️ Servings: 4</li>
</ul>


<h2>Ingredients</h2>

<ul>
<li>3 aubergines (900g)</li>
<li>300g spaghetti</li>
<li>100ml olive oil</li>
<li>5 garlic cloves, minced</li>
<li>1 chilli (or 1 tsp of dried chilli flakes)</li>
<li>2 x 400g tinned chopped tomatoes</li>
<li>1 teaspoon dried oregano</li>
<li>1 teaspoon caster sugar</li>
<li>Fresh basil</li>
</ul>


<h2>Directions</h2>

<ol>
<li>Preheat oven to 220c (fan), or gas mark 7.</li>
<li>Use a peeler to shave off alternating strips on your aubergines, so they looked striped, like zebras.</li>
<li>Then cut the aubergine widthways into 1cm thick slices. Place into a bowl with 75ml of olive oil, a good pinch of salt and black pepper. Coat the aubergines, then spread them onto two or three baking paper-lined trays. Roast for 30-35 minutes until dark brown.</li>
<li>Whilst the aubergines are cooking, put two tablespoons of olive oil into a frying pan or pot on a medium-high heat. Add garlic and chillis and fry for 1 minute (don&rsquo;t burn them!). Add tinned tomatoes, oregano, sugar and a pinch of salt and pepper to the pot. Reduce heat to medium low and cook until the sauce has thickened.</li>
<li>Cook the pasta according to packet instructions, once al dente, drain and retain some of the pasta water.</li>
<li>Once cooked, add the aubergine to the pasta sauce and mix well. Then add the spaghetti to the aubergine and sauce mixture, making sure everything is evenly coated. Add some of the pasta water if required to loosen the sauce, then top with fresh basil.</li>
<li>Check for seasoning, then serve immediately.</li>
</ol>


<h2>Contribution</h2>

<ul>
<li>James - <a href="https://jameskent.xyz">website</a></li>
</ul>


<p>;tags: italian pasta vegetables vegan</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title type="text">Glutenfree Pfannkuchen (pancakes)</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://based.cooking/glutenfree-pfannkuchen.html"/>
<id>https://based.cooking/glutenfree-pfannkuchen.html</id>
<published>2021-03-21T21:45:21Z</published>
<updated>2021-03-21T21:45:21Z</updated>
<author><name>lxgr-linux</name></author>
<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Glutenfree Pfannkuchen (pancakes)</h1>

<p><img src="pix/glutenfree-pfannkuchen.webp" alt="glutenfree pfannkuchen" /></p>

<p>A very easy recipe for glutenfree Pfannkuchen (german pancakes).</p>

<ul>
<li>⏲️ Prep time: 20 min</li>
<li>🍳Cook time: 10 min</li>
<li>🍽️ Servings: 1</li>
</ul>


<h2>Ingredients</h2>

<ul>
<li>100g glutenfree flour</li>
<li>200ml milk</li>
<li>50g sugar</li>
<li>2 eggs</li>
<li>a pinch of salt</li>
</ul>


<h2>Directions</h2>

<ol>
<li>Mix all ingredients in a bowl</li>
<li>Let the dought rest for ~15 mins</li>
<li>Heat a pan with a bit butter</li>
<li>For each pancake spread a ladle of dought in the pan and bake them at lower medium temperature until they are brown on both sides</li>
</ol>


<h2>Served with</h2>

<ul>
<li>Syrup</li>
<li>Cinnamon and sugar</li>
</ul>


<h2>Contribution</h2>

<ul>
<li>Lxgr - <a href="https://github.com/lxgr-linux">github</a></li>
</ul>


<p>;tags: basic, sweet, breakfast, german, pancake</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title type="text">Kalderetang Manok</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://based.cooking/kalderetang-manok.html"/>
<id>https://based.cooking/kalderetang-manok.html</id>
<published>2021-03-21T20:45:46Z</published>
<updated>2021-03-21T20:45:46Z</updated>
<author><name>Xzenia</name></author>
<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Kalderetang Manok</h1>

<p>Classic Filipino dish, great paired with freshly cooked rice and a bottle of Coca Cola.</p>

<ul>
<li>⏲️ Prep time: 30 min.</li>
<li>🍳Cook time: 1 hr.</li>
<li>🍽️ Servings: 5</li>
</ul>


<h2>Ingredients</h2>

<ul>
<li>1 lb of chicken</li>
<li>2 chopped potatoes</li>
<li>2 chopped carrots</li>
<li>1 chopped onion</li>
<li>2 chopped cloves of garlic</li>
<li>1 chopped tomato (optional)</li>
<li>3 cups of water</li>
<li>Tomato sauce</li>
<li>Chopped bell pepper</li>
<li>Dried peas</li>
<li>Liver spread</li>
<li>Fish sauce</li>
<li>Grated cheese</li>
</ul>


<h2>Directions</h2>

<ol>
<li>Sauté onions, garlic and (optional) tomato, in a pan of olive oil.</li>
<li>Put chicken and cook until brown, add 2 tablespoons of salt and pepper. (Note: Make sure the chicken is cook all the way through.)</li>
<li>Add fish sauce before adding water and let the chicken boil for a few minutes and then add tomato sauce.</li>
<li>Add potatoes, carrots, and liver spread. Mix the liver spread and let it boil until broth thickens, let it boil until carrots and potatoes are soft. Add more salt and pepper if needed.</li>
<li>Add dried peas, bell pepper and grated cheese and let it cook for a minute.</li>
<li>Cook until cheese melts before serving.</li>
</ol>


<h2>Contribution</h2>

<ul>
<li>Jess Calape - <a href="https://twitter.com/justjess1128">twitter</a></li>
</ul>


<p>;tags: filipino chicken</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title type="text">Sopa de Lentejas</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://based.cooking/lentejas.html"/>
<id>https://based.cooking/lentejas.html</id>
<published>2021-03-21T20:16:38Z</published>
<updated>2021-03-21T20:16:38Z</updated>
<author><name>Ignacio Ferrer</name></author>
<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Sopa de Lentejas</h1>

<p><img src="pix/lentejas.webp" alt="Lentejas" /></p>

<p>Traditional-spanish dish. Typical spanish!</p>

<ul>
<li>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min</li>
<li>🍳Cook time: 35 min</li>
<li>🍽️ Servings: 4-6</li>
</ul>


<h2>Ingredients</h2>

<ul>
<li>1 carrot, chopped</li>
<li>1 green bell pepper, chopped</li>
<li>4 garlic cloves, minced</li>
<li>1 large onion, chopped</li>
<li>1 cup dry brown lentils, soaked overnight and drained</li>
<li>2 plum tomatoes, chopped</li>
<li>2 cups water, or as needed</li>
<li>1 bay leaf</li>
<li>1 tbsp extra-virgin olive oil</li>
<li>&frac12; tsp of paprika</li>
<li>&frac14; spicy chorizo (optional)</li>
</ul>


<h2>Directions</h2>

<ol>
<li>Heat olive oil in a large pot over medium heat.</li>
<li>Add the onion, carrot, and bell pepper; cook and stir until vegetables begin to soften, about 5 minutes.</li>
<li>Stir in the garlic, tomatoes, chorizo and bay leaf; cook about 4 minutes.</li>
<li>Add lentils and water (water should be about an inch deeper than the level of the lentils).</li>
<li>Bring to a boil over high heat. Reduce heat to low; simmer, uncovered, until lentils are just cooked, 15 to 20 minutes.</li>
</ol>


<h2>Contribution</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/Nacchofer31">Ignacio Ferrer - Nacchofer31</a></li>
</ul>


<p>;tags: spanish traditional</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title type="text">Traditional bolognese sauce</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://based.cooking/traditional-bolognese-sauce.html"/>
<id>https://based.cooking/traditional-bolognese-sauce.html</id>
<published>2021-03-21T20:15:17Z</published>
<updated>2021-03-21T20:15:17Z</updated>
<author><name>yiusa</name></author>
<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Traditional bolognese sauce</h1>

<p>Basic bolognese sauce for lasagne or pasta dishes</p>

<ul>
<li>⏲️ Prep time: 45 min</li>
<li>🍳 Cook time: at least 4 hours</li>
</ul>


<h2>Ingredients</h2>

<ul>
<li>extra virgin olive oil</li>
<li>2 carrots</li>
<li>2 celery sticks</li>
<li>1 large onion</li>
<li>2 garlic cloves (optional, but not traditional)</li>
<li>200 grams pancetta (optional)</li>
<li>300 grams beef mince</li>
<li>350 grams pork mince</li>
<li>350 grams veal mince (if you cant find veal replace with pork)</li>
<li>140 grams concentrated tomato paste</li>
<li>690 grams diced tomatoes</li>
<li>water</li>
<li>1 can peeled tomatoes</li>
<li>1-2 glasses wine (whatever you have open)</li>
<li>1 glass of milk (optional)</li>
<li>1 glass of beef/vegetable stock (optional)</li>
</ul>


<h2>Directions</h2>

<ol>
<li>Finely dice the carrots, celery, onion and pancetta, if your blender can handle it you can optionally blend all this to speed it up.</li>
<li>Heat up a large saucepan or dutch oven on medium low heat and put enough olive oil in to cover the bottom of the pan.</li>
<li>Put in your diced veggies and pancetta and let it slowly sauté for about 10 minutes until everything is fragrant and soft.</li>
<li>If you are using garlic add it here and let it sweat for a minute</li>
<li>Add in your minced meat and break it up into small clumps about the size of a rice grain with a spoon, keep stiring until all your meat is lightly cooked.</li>
<li>Once all your meat is cooked and looks a bit grey add your wine, add enough to fully deglaze the pan (I usually add a little bit extra for the flavor)
stir it through until it has completely evaporated. (If you are using it you can also add the stock at this point)</li>
<li>Once your pan is somewhat dry you can add the tomato paste to the beef, let it cook for a minute to remove the slight metallic taste.</li>
<li>Add your canned and peeled tomatoes and use your spoon to break them up, you don&rsquo;t have to be too thorough since they will soften up while the sauce cooks.</li>
<li>add the diced tomatoes, fill the jar your tomatos came in with water give it a shake and add that to the pot, do the same with your can of peeled tomatoes.</li>
<li>lower your heat to the lowest setting and slightly cover the pan with your lid.</li>
<li>let it simmer for as long as you can wait, preferably at least 4 hours, if it starts getting a bit too dry you can add a bit more water to make sure the sauce doesn&rsquo;t burn.</li>
<li>Once it&rsquo;s done simmering for as long as you can muster and its nice and thick, the liquid should not come above your meat and should be pretty concentrated</li>
<li>You can add your glass of milk, let it simmer for 10 more minutes and serve.</li>
</ol>


<h2>Contribution</h2>

<p>Yiusa
-eth &lsquo;0x68f1317c6512f0267fa711cafb6c134ae968fa80&rsquo;</p>

<p>;tags: sauce italian pasta</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title type="text">Belgian pear syrup</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://based.cooking/belgian-pear-syrup.html"/>
<id>https://based.cooking/belgian-pear-syrup.html</id>
<published>2021-03-21T18:28:54Z</published>
<updated>2021-03-21T18:28:54Z</updated>
<author><name>yiusa</name></author>
<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Belgian pear syrup</h1>

<p>A delicious syrup that can be eaten on bread and used in a multitude of recipes.</p>

<ul>
<li>⏲️ Prep time: 30 min</li>
<li>🍳Cook time: 6 hours</li>
</ul>


<h2>Ingredients</h2>

<ul>
<li>7 pears (quality doesn&rsquo;t matter, you can argue that overripe pears are better because they have more suggar content)</li>
<li>3 apples</li>
<li>a small handfull of dates, raisins, dried appricots or prunes (optional, you can experiment with these they can bring some nice flavors)</li>
<li>150 grams sugar</li>
<li>1 glass of water</li>
<li>find sieve or cheese cloth</li>
<li>glass jar</li>
</ul>


<h2>Directions</h2>

<ol>
<li>Wash the outside of the fruit with water and cut it in 8 medium sized pieces, you don&rsquo;t have to core or deseed the fruit everything can go in the pot.</li>
<li>Place the fruit in a large pan with a thick bottom so you get even heat, i suggest you place the pears on the bottom since they don&rsquo;t burn as fast, add the glass of water.</li>
<li>If you are using them add the dried fruits at this point.</li>
<li>Put the heat as low as you can get it and let it all slowly stew for 3 hours, stiring every now and then.</li>
<li>At this point you can boil your glass jars to sterilize them, place them on a clean, dry towel.</li>
<li>When the fruit is done cooking for 3 hours grab your sieve or cleese cloth and place it over a bowl, run your fruit through it until you have extracted all the clear liquid, you can discard the pulp.</li>
<li>Quickly rins the pot with water so its clean and add the fruit liquid back, put back on the stove.</li>
<li>Add the sugar, add a bit less sugar if you also used dried fruits.</li>
<li>Cook for another 2 hours, after that stir every so often, Be careful with the stirring if you stir too often it might caramelize too quickly.</li>
<li>After two to two and a halve hours your syrup should be nearly done</li>
<li>At this point its up to you on how thick you want your syrup to be, a good way to test the viscosity is to drop a little bit on a cold plate or your countertop to see how it is at room temperature.</li>
<li>when you are happy with the viscosity poor the syrup into your sterilized jars and immeadiatly seal them.</li>
</ol>


<h2>Contribution</h2>

<p>Yiusa
-eth &lsquo;0x68f1317c6512f0267fa711cafb6c134ae968fa80&rsquo;</p>

<p>;tags: syrup fruit belgian</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title type="text">Kvass</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://based.cooking/kvass.html"/>
<id>https://based.cooking/kvass.html</id>
<published>2021-03-21T18:27:29Z</published>
<updated>2021-03-21T18:27:29Z</updated>
<author><name>Holsterbau</name></author>
<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Kvass</h1>

<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kvass">Kvass</a> is a Slavic fermented beverage which is both simple to make and rich in flavour.</p>

<ul>
<li>⏲️ Prep time: ~30 min</li>
<li>⌛ Fermentation time: ~1 week</li>
</ul>


<h2>Ingredients</h2>

<ul>
<li>100 g of raisins</li>
<li>100 g of sugar</li>
<li>3 slices of black bread (e.g. pumpernickel bread, rye bread)</li>
<li>1-2 lemons</li>
<li>1 pkg (7 g) of active dry yeast</li>
<li><em>Optional:</em>

<ul>
<li><em>A handful of coffee beans</em></li>
<li><em>Non-citrus fruits (e.g. plums, apples, kiwi)</em></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2>Directions</h2>

<ol>
<li>Bring 1 L of water in a pot to a boil.</li>
<li>Burn black bread in a toaster or in an oven until it is thoroughly scorched to blackness on the outside.</li>
<li>Once the water has come to boil, remove off heat. Add burned black bread, a handful of raisins, a few slices of lemon, and coffee beans to the pot.</li>
<li>Leave contents of the pot to cool down to room temperature.</li>
<li>Filter out everything from the pot through a strainer, and pour contents into a separate, sterilized container. Add sugar and yeast into
the container, and stir until sugar is dissolved. This starts the fermentation process. The amount of sugar in this recipe should yield 1.0%-2.5% alcohol
by total volume at the end of the fermentation process.</li>
<li>Add rest of raisins, and non-citrus fruits of your choice. The fruits will positively impact flavour of the final product.</li>
<li>If mixture is not already in a mason jar, pour the mixture into a sterile mason jar, and seal the lid. Place the jar in a warm place (26-30°C; 79-86°F),
and let it ferment for a week, or until it stops bubbling.</li>
<li>Remove all raisins and fruits from the jar.</li>
<li>Squeeze lemon juice from lemons into the mixture. You may drink the now-complete kvass right away, or refrigerate it before drinking.</li>
</ol>


<h2>Contribution</h2>

<ul>
<li>Holsterbau - <a href="https://github.com/Holsterbau">website</a></li>
</ul>


<p>;tags: drink</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title type="text">Francesinha</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://based.cooking/francesinha.html"/>
<id>https://based.cooking/francesinha.html</id>
<published>2021-03-21T17:35:15Z</published>
<updated>2021-03-21T17:35:15Z</updated>
<author><name>Artur Mancha</name></author>
<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Francesinha</h1>

<p>Francesinha is a traditional sandwich from the city of Porto. The francesinha in its special sandwich variation consists of sausage, fresh sausage, ham, cold meat and beef steak, covered with melted cheese.</p>

<h2>Based Ingredients</h2>

<ul>
<li>bread</li>
<li>linguiça</li>
<li>ham</li>
<li>Portuguese cheese</li>
<li>beef meat</li>
</ul>


<h2>Sauce Ingredients</h2>

<ul>
<li>blonde beer</li>
<li>fried tomato sauce</li>
<li>port wine</li>
<li>beef broth</li>
<li>salted butter</li>
<li>onion</li>
<li>minced garlic</li>
<li>cornstarch</li>
<li>olive oil</li>
<li>piripiri (Portuguese chili)</li>
</ul>


<h2>Directions for the sauce</h2>

<ol>
<li>In a big saucepan, heat the olive oil and add the garlic and the onions. Cook them until golden.</li>
<li>Pour the beer and simmer until the alcohol evaporates. It&rsquo;s around 5 minutes.</li>
<li>Pour the beef broth, the fried tomato sauce, the port wine, the Piripiri and the butter to give shine to the sauce. Add the cornstarch slowly avoiding lumps. Simmer for a couple of minutes until the sauce looks thick.</li>
</ol>


<h2>Directions for the Francesinhas</h2>

<ol>
<li>Preheat the oven to 180 C (350 F)</li>
<li>Cook the beef chopped in small strings. Season with salt and black pepper.</li>
<li>Cook the linguiças sliced in half lengthwise.</li>
<li>Take 4 slices of bread for each Francesinha. Cut the center of two slices to make room for the filling. The other two will be the bottom and top of the francesinhas.</li>
<li>Fill the bread with the sausages, the beef and the ham roughly chopped. Cover the francesinhas with the cheese and melt in the oven for 5 minutes.</li>
<li>Cover with the sauce and serve with french fries.</li>
</ol>


<h2>Contribution</h2>

<ul>
<li>Artur Mancha &ndash; <a href="https://pleroma.pt/@lisbonjoker">Pleroma</a></li>
</ul>


<p>;tags: portuguese beef</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title type="text">Spaghetti alla puttanesca</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://based.cooking/spaghetti-alla-puttanesca.html"/>
<id>https://based.cooking/spaghetti-alla-puttanesca.html</id>
<published>2021-03-21T17:33:55Z</published>
<updated>2021-03-21T17:33:55Z</updated>
<author><name>Postbellum</name></author>
<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Spaghetti alla puttanesca</h1>

<p>Easy and delicious italian dish. Spaghetti alla puttanesca entice you for the savory sauce that surrounds them: peeled tomatoes, capers, &ldquo;Gaeta&rdquo; olives,  and anchovy fillets give these spaghetti a unique taste.</p>

<ul>
<li>⏲️Prep time: ~18 min</li>
<li>🍳 Cook time: 6-7 min</li>
<li>🍽️Servings: 4</li>
</ul>


<h2>Ingredients</h2>

<ul>
<li>Pot of water</li>
<li>320g italian spaghetti</li>
<li>2 garlic cloves</li>
<li>10g salted capers</li>
<li>25g anchovies in oil</li>
<li>800g peeled tomatoes &ldquo;sugo&rdquo;</li>
<li>1 bunch of parsley</li>
<li>100g Gaeta olives</li>
<li>2 chopped chillies</li>
<li>A pinch of salt</li>
</ul>


<h2>Directions</h2>

<ol>
<li>Wash capers from salt, then cut them</li>
<li>Pit and crush Gaeta olives</li>
<li>Wash and chop the bunch of parsley</li>
<li>Put a pot of water on the fire, it&rsquo;ll be used for cooking the pasta. Let it boil and then add salt</li>
<li>Pour the oil, the peeled garlic cloves and the chopped dry chilli peppers into a large pan</li>
<li>Add the anchovy fillets and capers</li>
<li>Brown over medium heat for 5 minutes, stirring often, so the anchovies will melt</li>
<li>Now add peeled tomatoes &ldquo;sugo&rdquo;; mix it with a spoon and cook for another 10 minutes over medium heat</li>
<li>Let&rsquo;s now cook spaghetti after the water is boiled for 6/7 minutes (al dente cooking)</li>
<li>When the sauce is ready, remove the garlic cloves</li>
<li>Add crushed olives and chopped parsley</li>
<li>Drain spaghetti directly in the pan and sauté it for half a minute</li>
<li>The dish is ready</li>
</ol>


<h2>Contribution</h2>

<ul>
<li>Postbellum <a href="https://github.com/postbellum">GitHub</a></li>
</ul>


<p>;tags: italian pasta</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title type="text">Lamb Biriyani</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://based.cooking/lamb-biriyani.html"/>
<id>https://based.cooking/lamb-biriyani.html</id>
<published>2021-03-21T17:22:01Z</published>
<updated>2021-03-21T17:22:01Z</updated>
<author><name>Ram</name></author>
<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Lamb Biriyani</h1>

<p>This recipe makes an Southern Indian (Tamil) style Lamb biriyani that has been adapted to a more western audience (aka a bit less spicy)
and can be made with either Lamb or Mutton. Best served with a sauce such as an Onion Raitha <a href="https://based.cooking/onion-raitha">website</a>.</p>

<p><img src="pix/lamb-biriyani.webp" alt="Lamb Biriyani" /></p>

<p>A plated rendering of the dish, made with Mutton. Makes a really hearty ,meaty and delicious dish. The dishes uses a rice to meat ratio of 2:3.
PS: the biriyani tastes better the longer it&rsquo;s allowed to soak in it&rsquo;s flavour after cooking.</p>

<ul>
<li>⏲️ Prep time: 30 min</li>
<li>🍳Cook time: 1 hr 15 min</li>
<li>🍽️ Servings: 4</li>
</ul>


<h2>Ingredients</h2>

<ul>
<li>4-5 pods of Cardamom</li>
<li>2-3 Bay leaves</li>
<li>3-4 Cinnamon Sticks</li>
<li>8 Cloves</li>
<li>400gm Basmati Rice</li>
<li>600gm Mutton / Lamb (Boneless)</li>
<li>2 Onions (Preferably Red)</li>
<li>2 Tomatoes</li>
<li>1 Green chilli (Optional)</li>
<li>10 Garlic pearls</li>
<li>5cm piece of Ginger</li>
<li>&frac12; Tbsp of Garam Masala</li>
<li>1 Tbsp of Chilli Powder or Hungarian Smoked Paprika</li>
<li>Juice of &frac12; Lemon or 1 tsp of Vinegar</li>
<li>Dash of Tumeric Powder</li>
<li>Dash of Curry Powder</li>
<li>1 Sprig of Mint / Coriander (Garnish)</li>
</ul>


<h2>Directions</h2>

<ol>
<li>Wash the rice till the water turns clear and let the rice soak for at least 30 mins.</li>
<li>Chop the tomatoes down into tiny cubes and the onions into julienne slices. Grind the ginger and garlic into a paste.</li>
<li>For the green chilli slice it midway to maintain it in one piece.</li>
<li>In a big pot, Add 30 ml of neutral oil and toast the spices for 30 sec on medium heat.</li>
<li>Add the onions and saute for around 3 min.</li>
<li>Add the tomatoes, ginger and garlic paste and saute for another 3 min.</li>
<li>Add the mutton/ lamb and 2 cups (500ml) of water. Add one Tbsp of salt.</li>
<li>Turn the heat up to high and add the green chilli, tumeric powder, chilli powder and 2 Tbsp of salt and let the mutton cook for about 40 -50 min.</li>
<li>Ensure that the pot does not run out of water and top up with more if required.</li>
<li>Add about 2 cups of water or to about 800 gm of water in the pot while accounting for water left in the pot (1:2 ratio of rice to water).</li>
<li>Once boiling again, Add the rice, Garam Masala and Lemon juice / Vinegar to the pot.</li>
<li>Once 80% of the standing water has evaporated, Turn to the heat down to as low as possible and check the salt and spice levels and add more as required.</li>
<li>Now with a lid on, let the pot simmer for another 10 mins.</li>
<li>Serve with onion raitha and boiled Eggs and Garnish with coriander or mint sprigs. Enjoy !</li>
</ol>


<h2>Contribution</h2>

<p>Ram Pari - <a href="https://github.com/ramkpari">website</a></p>

<p>Donate -> ETH: <code>bc1q763s4ud0hgfa66ce64gyh6tsss49vyk5cqcm6w</code></p>

<p>;tags: lamb mutton indian</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title type="text">Onion Raitha (Indian Tzatziki)</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://based.cooking/onion-raitha.html"/>
<id>https://based.cooking/onion-raitha.html</id>
<published>2021-03-21T17:22:01Z</published>
<updated>2021-03-21T17:22:01Z</updated>
<author><name>Ram</name></author>
<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Onion Raitha (Indian Tzatziki)</h1>

<p>Raitha is an yogurt-based Indian style sauce that goes great with rice dishes such as Pilau and Biriyani. It&rsquo;s quite similar to
a greek Tzatziki and is quick and quite easy to make. It&rsquo;s great especially with super spicy indian dishes as it
provides as a sweet and cooling effect.</p>

<ul>
<li>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min</li>
<li>🍳Cook time: 2 min</li>
<li>🍽️ Servings: 4</li>
</ul>


<h2>Ingredients</h2>

<ul>
<li>500 gm of Greek Yogurt</li>
<li>One Red onion</li>
<li>50 gm of Cucumber</li>
<li>Sprigs of Mint</li>
<li>Dash of Honey</li>
<li>Hint of Chilli Powder (Spicy option)/ Hint of sugar (Sweet option)</li>
</ul>


<h2>Directions</h2>

<ol>
<li>Chop the onion into tiny cubes (0.5-1cm or 3/8 inches sized cubes)</li>
<li>Slice the cucumber into tiny strips (Julienne). Hand crush the mint.</li>
<li>Prep the serving bowl with yogurt and add the onions and cucumber.</li>
<li>Add the mint, honey, 1 tsp of salt and the sugar/chilli powder (Depending on the sweet/spicy choice)</li>
<li>Mix well and serve. Garnish with additional mint as required.</li>
</ol>


<h2>Contribution</h2>

<p>Ram Pari - <a href="https://github.com/ramkpari">website</a></p>

<p>Donate -> ETH: <code>bc1q763s4ud0hgfa66ce64gyh6tsss49vyk5cqcm6w</code></p>

<p>;tags: quick sauce indian</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title type="text">Assam Tea</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://based.cooking/assam-tea.html"/>
<id>https://based.cooking/assam-tea.html</id>
<published>2021-03-21T17:16:30Z</published>
<updated>2021-03-21T17:16:30Z</updated>
<author><name>Chandra Kiran Reddy</name></author>
<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Assam Tea</h1>

<p><img src="pix/assam-tea.webp" alt="Assam Tea" /></p>

<p>This is a simple Assam tea recipe.</p>

<ul>
<li>⏲️ Prep time: 1 min</li>
<li>🍳Cook time: 5 min</li>
<li>🍽️ Servings: 1</li>
</ul>


<h2>Ingredients</h2>

<ul>
<li>2 teaspoons of Assam Tea</li>
<li>150 ml of fresh water</li>
<li>Sugar (Optional)</li>
<li>Milk (Optional)</li>
</ul>


<h2>Directions</h2>

<ol>
<li>Add 150 ml of water to a small pan and bring it to boil.</li>
<li>Then add 2 teaspoons of tea into it and reduce the heat to low.</li>
<li>Strain the tea using a tea filter into a cup.</li>
<li>Add sugar and milk to taste</li>
</ol>


<h2>Contribution</h2>

<ul>
<li>Chandra Kiran - <a href="https://github.com/ackr-8">GitHub</a></li>
</ul>


<p>;tags: drink quick</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title type="text">No-knead Bread</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://based.cooking/no-knead-bread.html"/>
<id>https://based.cooking/no-knead-bread.html</id>
<published>2021-03-21T17:13:11Z</published>
<updated>2021-03-21T17:13:11Z</updated>
<author><name>Christian Chapman</name></author>
<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>No-knead Bread</h1>

<p><img src="pix/no-knead-bread-1.webp" alt="Finished bread" /></p>

<ul>
<li>⏲️ Prep time: 13 h</li>
<li>🍳Cook time: 50 m</li>
<li>🍽️ Servings: 8-12 slices</li>
</ul>


<h2>Ingredients</h2>

<ul>
<li>3 c flour</li>
<li>1 + &frac14; tbsp salt</li>
<li>&frac14; tsp instant yeast or 1.25/4 tsp active dry yeast</li>
<li>1 + &frac12; + 1/8 cups hot water</li>
<li>Oven-safe pan</li>
</ul>


<h2>Directions</h2>

<ol>
<li>Mix the dry ingredients then add the hot water. It should come out as a firm dough.</li>
<li>Leave the dough at room temperature for 12 hours.
<img src="pix/no-knead-bread-2.webp" alt="Before baking" /></li>
<li>Preheat oven and pan to 450 F.</li>
<li>Bake for 30 minutes covered (e.g. aluminum foil), then 20 minutes uncovered.</li>
</ol>


<h2>Contribution</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="ebn0.net">By enthdegree.</a></li>
</ul>


<p>;tags: bread baking</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title type="text">## Savory Squash</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://based.cooking/savory-squash.html"/>
<id>https://based.cooking/savory-squash.html</id>
<published>2021-03-21T15:49:19Z</published>
<updated>2021-03-21T17:13:11Z</updated>
<author><name>Luke Smith</name></author>
<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Savory Squash</h2>

<ul>
<li>Prep Time: 5 mins</li>
<li>Cook Time: 1 Hour</li>
</ul>


<h2>Ingredients</h2>

<ul>
<li>1 Butternut Squash</li>
<li>&frac12; Stick of butter</li>
<li>Salt, to taste</li>
<li>St. Augur Blue Cheese</li>
<li>Chives</li>
</ul>


<h2>Directions</h2>

<ol>
<li>Peel Butternut squash and discard both ends. Cut in half lengthwise, scoop and discard seeds. Cut in half lengthwise again.</li>
<li>Place face down on greased baking sheet. Rotate to roast the other face after 20 minutes, Check at 45 mins with a toothpick for softness.</li>
<li>Cut up into 2 inch chunks and toss into stand mixer. Mix on high and add a half stick of butter and salt to taste. Stir in half of the St. Augur blue cheese.</li>
<li>Pour into casserole dish. Stir in any extra blue cheese to taste or crumble on top. Lower oven to 300 and bake the mashed squash for 15 minutes.</li>
<li>Garnish with chopped chives on top.</li>
</ol>


<h2>Contribution</h2>

<ul>
<li>Joe Powerhouse, BTC: 1KPxw9js2VukakhMv2wUUFUQZnHQL842ju</li>
</ul>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title type="text">Stoemp</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://based.cooking/stoemp.html"/>
<id>https://based.cooking/stoemp.html</id>
<published>2021-03-21T14:58:44Z</published>
<updated>2021-03-21T14:58:44Z</updated>
<author><name>Alexey Porotnikov</name></author>
<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Stoemp</h1>

<p>Mashed potatoes in Belgian style</p>

<ul>
<li>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min</li>
<li>🍳Cook time: 30 min</li>
<li>🍽️ Servings: 4</li>
</ul>


<h2>Ingredients</h2>

<ul>
<li>500g potatoes</li>
<li>300g carrots</li>
<li>100g bacon</li>
<li>50g butter</li>
<li>100ml heavy cream</li>
<li>&frac12; teaspoon ground nutmeg</li>
</ul>


<h2>Directions</h2>

<ol>
<li>Cut bacon into bits.</li>
<li>Sauté bacon until well colored.</li>
<li>Peel and dice into small chunks potatoes, peel and slice carrots.</li>
<li>Boil for 20-25 minutes potatoes and carrots in salted water.</li>
<li>Drain vegetables and mash with a fork, so that the texture remains slightly chunky.</li>
<li>Mix with bacon bits, butter, cream, nutmeg, salt, pepper.</li>
</ol>


<h2>Contribution</h2>

<p>https://github.com/alpo</p>

<p>;tags: belgian</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title type="text">Nashville Chicken Sandwich</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://based.cooking/nashville-chicken.html"/>
<id>https://based.cooking/nashville-chicken.html</id>
<published>2021-03-21T14:03:04Z</published>
<updated>2021-03-21T17:30:46Z</updated>
<author><name>marttoygoy4</name></author>
<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Nashville Chicken Sandwich</h1>

<p>If you love spicy foods and chicken then this Nashville Hot Chicken sandwich recipe is just for you. It takes some time with prepping and process but when you take that first bite all the effort will be worth it. It’s unlike any other fried chicken recipe that includes double frying your chicken and using the same cooking oil from your fry as a sauce for the Nashville Hot Chicken spice.</p>

<p>Nashville Hot Chicken was invented by a man named Thorton Prince. It is said that he came home late one night and whipped this dish up randomly. Could you imagine creating this staple of a dish late night after coming home from an evening of festivities, blows my mind. Let’s get into the recipe now.</p>

<ul>
<li>Prep time: 20 min</li>
<li>Cook time: 30 min</li>
<li>Servings: 4</li>
</ul>


<h2>Ingredients</h2>

<p>Batter
-2 Cups Buttermilk
-1/3 Cup Hot sauce</p>

<p>Flour
-2 &frac12; Cups All-purpose flour
-3 tbsp Cornstarch
-3 tbsp Seasoned salt
-1 tbsp Paprika
-2 tsp Cayenne pepper
-2 tsp Black pepper
-1 tbsp Garlic powder
-1 tbsp Onion powder
-2 tsp Dry mustard powder</p>

<p>Nashville Hot Chicken
-2 tbsp Nashville Hot Chicken seasoning
-2 tbsp Adobo honey seasoning
-2 tbsp Dark brown sugar
-1 tsp Chili powder
-1 tsp Garlic powder
-1 tsp Smoked paprika
-1 &frac12; Cups Cooking oil Used to fry the chicken</p>

<p>Sauce For the Buns
-3 tbsp Mayo
-1 tbsp Ketchup
-2 tbsp Sweet relish
-1 tbsp Hot sauce</p>

<h2>Directions</h2>

<ol>
<li>Prep your chicken by trimming it into less than a &frac12;" patties for frying.</li>
<li>Prepare your batter and flour in two separate bowls.</li>
<li>Dunk your chicken into the flour, then batter and then flour again. While your chicken is sitting with the battered flour pour 2 &frac12; cups of cooking oil into your pan over medium heat or 350 degrees. Let it come to temp, about 20 mins.</li>
<li>Once your oil has reached the temp of 350, go ahead and fry 3-4 pieces of chicken at one time. You are going to fry for 7 mins (flipping at the midway point) and then pull the chicken and let sit for 5 mins then refry for the second time 3 mins, this depends on the thickness of the chicken.</li>
<li>Now that your chicken is fried make sure you have a wire rack with a sheet pan under it so the crispy chicken can sit and rest on. During this resting time, you are going to add your Nashville Hot Chicken seasoning together with 1 &frac12; cups of the cooking oil you just used. It will simmer but quickly whisk until it comes still. Now you want to brush that amazing sauce all over the crispy chicken or dunk it.</li>
<li>Have some toasted buns ready and create your sandwich. First, you want to sauce your top and bottom buns, add shredded romaine lettuce, chicken patty, tomato and then complete with the top bun for an amazingly delicious creation.</li>
<li>Feed the family and enjoy! This one gets spicy, >E  N  J  O Y&lt; :)</li>
</ol>


<h2>Contribution</h2>

<p><a href="https://grillnationbbq.com/wprm_print/1538">https://grillnationbbq.com/wprm_print/1538</a></p>

<ul>
<li>BBQ-Nation <em>Credit</em> <a href="https://grillnationbbq.com/wprm_print/1538">website</a></li>
</ul>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title type="text">Stoofvlees</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://based.cooking/stoofvlees.html"/>
<id>https://based.cooking/stoofvlees.html</id>
<published>2021-03-21T13:57:51Z</published>
<updated>2021-03-21T13:57:51Z</updated>
<author><name>yiusa</name></author>
<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Stoofvlees</h1>

<p>This is a traditional belgian stew made with cheap, though beef cuts, beer and onions.
Traditionally eaten with fries and chicory salad.</p>

<ul>
<li>⏲️ Prep time: 30 min</li>
<li>🍳Cook time: 2 to 4 hours</li>
<li>🍽️ Servings: 4</li>
</ul>


<h2>Ingredients</h2>

<ul>
<li>2 Large onions</li>
<li>1 tablespoon butter</li>
<li>1kg chuck roast, cut in bite-sized pieces</li>
<li>2 33cl bottles of brown beer</li>
<li>2 bayleaves</li>
<li>2 twigs of thyme</li>
<li>1 clove (spice)</li>
<li>2 tablespoons of belgian apple/pear syrup (optional, ill write up a recipe for this soon)</li>
<li>2 teaspoons of vinegar</li>
<li>1 slice of bread</li>
<li>mustard</li>
</ul>


<h2>Directions</h2>

<ol>
<li>Peel the onions and cut them into medium sized pieces, don&rsquo;t cut the onion too small.</li>
<li>Place a large saucepan or dutch oven on low heat and add 1 tbsp butter. Once melted add your onions, cook until translucent.</li>
<li>While your onions are cooking place a large frying pan on medium high heat and melt your second spoon of butter.</li>
<li>Fry up your beef until it has a nice brown crust, to prevent overcrowding the pan you should sear the meat in seperate batches, be careful to not burn the fond on the bottom of the pan.season the meat with salt and pepper while its cooking.</li>
<li>When a piece of beef is done searing add it to the pot with the onions, once you&rsquo;re done searing all of your meat add your beer to the frying pan and use it to deglaze, scrape off all the pieces stuck to the frying pan.</li>
<li>Add the beer you used to deglaze to the pot with the onions and beef.</li>
<li>Add the bayleaf and thyme, optionally you can bind them together with some kitchen twine so they are easier to pick out later.</li>
<li>Add your clove and if you have it the syrup.</li>
<li>Take your piece of preferably brown bread and generously spread it with mustard on both sides, place it in the sauce.</li>
<li>let it simmer on low heat, stirring once every 10-15 minutes. when the sauce has reached your desired thicknes place a lid on the pot.</li>
<li>The cooking time will depend on the quality of your meat, start checking the if your meat is done once its been simmering for about 2 hours.</li>
<li>The meat is done when the pieces hold together when gently stirring the sauce, but are easily cut with a fork or spoon.</li>
<li>Finish the sauce by gently stirring in the vinegar to brighten up the flavors and serve.

<h2>Contribution</h2></li>
</ol>


<p>Yiusa
-eth &lsquo;0x68f1317c6512f0267fa711cafb6c134ae968fa80&rsquo;</p>

<p>;tags: beef stew belgian</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title type="text">Spanish Tortilla</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://based.cooking/spanish-tortilla.html"/>
<id>https://based.cooking/spanish-tortilla.html</id>
<published>2021-03-21T13:46:20Z</published>
<updated>2021-03-21T17:26:55Z</updated>
<author><name>SimonBlancoE</name></author>
<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Spanish Tortilla</h1>

<p><img src="pix/spanish-tortilla.webp" alt="Spanish Tortilla" /></p>

<ul>
<li>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min</li>
<li>🍳 Cook time: 35 min</li>
<li>🍽️ Servings: 6</li>
</ul>


<h2>Ingredients</h2>

<ul>
<li>8 free-range eggs</li>
<li>1 kg of potatoes</li>
<li>1 white onion</li>
<li>Extra virgin olive oil</li>
</ul>


<h2>Instructions</h2>

<ol>
<li>Peel, rinse and dry the potatoes.</li>
<li>Cut the potatoes into thin slices. Put in a bowl, add salt to taste and stir.</li>
<li>Put a nonstick frying pan on the fire and add enough olive oil to fry all the potato slices.</li>
<li>Add the potato slices already salted and let them cook for approximately 20 minutes over low heat.</li>
<li>While the potatoes are frying, beat the eggs in a bowl. Peel and cut the onion as finely as possible.</li>
<li>Add olive oil in another frying pan and slowly fry the onion until it gets a slightly golden color.</li>
<li>Drain the onion and add it to the bowl with the beaten egg.</li>
<li>Remove the potatoes from the pan with a slotted spoon, draining the oil away as much as possible, and add them to the bowl with the onion and egg.</li>
<li>Let the mixture rest for at least 5 minutes so all the flavors come together. Give it a very gentle stir from time to time.</li>
<li>Remove the oil from the pan you used to fry the potatoes. Use the pan to cook the mixture over medium-high fire for about 5 minutes.</li>
<li>Flip it over with the help of a big plate and cook the other side for another 5 minutes.</li>
</ol>


<h2>Notes</h2>

<ul>
<li>Things like the slicing of the potato, the amount of salt and how curdled is the inner part of the tortilla depend on your own taste. Don&rsquo;t be afraid to experiment!</li>
</ul>


<h2>Contribution</h2>

<p>OctopusOnFire - <a href="https://www.minds.com/OctopusOnFire/">Minds</a></p>

<p>;tags: spanish potato eggs tortilla</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title type="text">Swedish Pancakes</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://based.cooking/swedish-pancakes.html"/>
<id>https://based.cooking/swedish-pancakes.html</id>
<published>2021-03-21T13:31:28Z</published>
<updated>2021-03-21T13:31:28Z</updated>
<author><name>i3oges</name></author>
<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Swedish Pancakes</h1>

<p><img src="pix/swedish-pancakes-00.webp" alt="Swedish Pancakes" /></p>

<ul>
<li>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min</li>
<li>🍳Cook time: 30 min</li>
<li>🍽️ Servings: 4</li>
</ul>


<h2>Ingredients</h2>

<ul>
<li>3 Eggs, beaten</li>
<li>1 tsp Salt</li>
<li>1 tbsp Sugar</li>
<li>1 cup Flour</li>
<li>1 - 2/3 cups Milk</li>
<li>6-8 tbsp Butter</li>
</ul>


<h2>Instructions</h2>

<ol>
<li>At medium/low heat begin melting the butter, and continue with beating eggs in large bowl, add salt, sugar, milk, flour and mix.</li>
<li>Add melted butter while stirring batter.</li>
<li>Use about &frac12; cup batter on griddle and tilt until spread evenly over griddle surface.</li>
<li>When edges of pancake start to firm-up use spatula and free up the outside inch or two to achieve a clean removal for flipping later.</li>
<li>First side will take about a minute or more the second side will take half that time. Pick up at middle of pancake with spatula then place on plate and fold over. The pancake will then be four layers thick 10" x 2" long. Serve with syrup on top or anything you choose, my wife likes peanut butter and I prefer to spread a little butter on it before adding syrup. Maybe you prefer adding fruits of your choice.</li>
</ol>


<p><img src="pix/swedish-pancakes-01.webp" alt="Swedish Pancakes" /></p>

<h2>Contribution</h2>

<p>Matt Bogenhagen</p>

<p>;tags: breakfast swedish</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
</feed>
