<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">Based Cooking</title>
<subtitle type="text">blog</subtitle>
<updated>2021-03-20T15:05:05Z</updated>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://based.cooking/"/>
<id>https://based.cooking/atom.xml</id>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://based.cooking//atom.xml"/>
<entry>
<title type="text">Älplermagronen (Alpine macaroni)</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://based.cooking/aelplermagronen.html"/>
<id>https://based.cooking/aelplermagronen.html</id>
<published>2021-03-20T16:04:10Z</published>
<updated>2021-03-20T16:04:10Z</updated>
<author><name>Joshix</name></author>
<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Älplermagronen (Alpine macaroni)</h1>

<p>A swiss favorite, <em>Älplermagronen</em> combines pretty much everything you have at your disposal in your alpine chalet.
It's the definition of comfort food for the Swiss.</p>

<p>Serves 5-6.</p>

<p>Cooking time: ~30 minutes</p>

<h2>Ingredients</h2>

<ul>
<li>~150g (1/3 lb) bacon cubes</li>
<li>3 onions (medium size)</li>
<li>400g (15 oz) potatoes (firm/waxy)</li>
<li>2L (1/2 gal) milk</li>
<li>200g (7oz) macaroni (dry weight)</li>
<li>~150g (1/3 lb) medium soft cheese. Appenzeller works best. Gruyère would be my go-to alternative.</li>
<li>a jar of apple sauce</li>
</ul>

<h2>Directions</h2>

<ol>
<li>Fry bacon cubes in pot (this pot will be used for everything so choose an appropriately large one)</li>
<li>Cut onions into half-rings and let them sweat in the same pot. Add some butter if your bacon was not fatty enough.</li>
<li>Peel potatoes and cut them into ~1 cm/half inch cubes</li>
<li>When the onions have become sufficiently cooked, add potatoes.</li>
<li>Top everything with milk and let the potatoes cook for about 10 minutes.</li>
<li>Add macaroni and the remaining milk to cover everything. Most of the milk will be absorbed by the macaroni.</li>
<li>Shred your cheese.</li>
<li>A minute or two before the macaroni are done, add the shredded cheese into the pot. It should appear a bit too runny in the pot. While cooling it will increase in viscosity quite a bit. If the final texture is not creamy enough it is most likely due to using the wrong cheese.</li>
<li>Season to taste. (Needs quite a bit of salt). Nutmeg also works well here.</li>
<li>Serve with apple sauce. Should be eaten together, not as a dessert.</li>
</ol>

<h2>Contributors</h2>

<ul>
<li><strong>Alexander Bocken</strong> -- <a href="mailto:alexander@bocken.org">contact</a></li>
</ul>

<p>;tags: swiss pork potato</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title type="text">Aljotta</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://based.cooking/aljotta.html"/>
<id>https://based.cooking/aljotta.html</id>
<published>2021-03-20T16:04:10Z</published>
<updated>2021-03-20T16:04:10Z</updated>
<author><name>Joshix</name></author>
<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Aljotta</h1>

<p><img src="pix/aljotta.webp" alt="aljotta" /></p>

<p>Aljotta, 'jo' as in "Yo!", is a light fish soup with roots in french bouillabaisse and similarly refers to the method of serving the fish that are cooked in it. The most appropriate fish to use for both the stock and the accompanying meal are 'clean' white fish that don't turn the broth cloudy, ideally stargazers, monkfish, red gurnard, and moray eels but also hake, mullets, cod and haddock. There are a some variants; restaurant versions could very well include lemon juice and shellfish which I don't associate with aljotta. Rice eventually became a staple with it and how much you put in is up to you. I recommend just a little, in fact, there are no ingredient amounts, the picture should give you an idea of the density you're going for. <strong>Fresh herbs are a must</strong>.</p>

<h2>Ingredients</h2>

<ul>
<li>Fish stock (see 2.)</li>
<li>Fish, raw</li>
<li>Onion, roughly chopped</li>
<li>Garlic, sliced or diced</li>
<li>Tomatos, chopped</li>
<li>frying oil/lard</li>
<li>Extra virgin olive oil</li>
<li>Marjoram</li>
<li>Black pepper (optional)</li>
<li>Mint, small amount (optional, I never use it myself as it's too overpowering)</li>
<li>Lemon wedge/juice (optional, also overpowering)</li>
<li>Rice (optional)</li>
</ul>

<h2>Directions</h2>

<ol>
<li>Cook some rice and set aside. White short-grain is best but other types will do as long as it's not starchy. Don't use arborio or sushi rice.</li>
<li>Prepare the stock, possibly the day before, by boiling fish and fish bones in a tall stock pot on medium heat for 1-2 hours. It's customary to have loose chunks of fish in the soup so you can boil the fish and seperate the meat as it starts to cook. As an example, the head, tail, skin and spine from the <a href="https://based.cooking/fried-anglerfish-fillet">anglerfish fillet recipe</a> were used to make stock, then half a fillet and meat that separated from the offal became part of the soup.</li>
<li>In a pot, heat some oil on low heat and add in the onions. Saute until translucent.</li>
<li>Add the garlic, tomato, herbs and salt if desired. Switch to medium heat, stirring occationally until the water starts to boil.</li>
<li>Add the fish and let simmer on low heat until the fish are cooked thoroughly, being careful not to break them. Turn the heat off and add the olive oil.</li>
<li>Take the fish out to be served seperately. They are traditionally served topped with olive oil and a squeeze of lemon with steamed vegetables.</li>
<li>If you are using lemon juice or rice, add them to each serving according to your preference.</li>
<li>Leave some for tomorrow. It always tastes better the next day.</li>
</ol>

<h2>Contribution</h2>

<p>Shou, <a href="https://shouganai.xyz">website</a></p>

<p>;tags: fish soup mediterranian</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title type="text">Almeirim Stone Soup</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://based.cooking/almeirim-stone-soup.html"/>
<id>https://based.cooking/almeirim-stone-soup.html</id>
<published>2021-03-20T16:04:10Z</published>
<updated>2021-03-20T16:04:10Z</updated>
<author><name>Joshix</name></author>
<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Almeirim Stone Soup</h1>

<p>It is truly emblematic of Portuguese cuisine, as it uses all of the ingredients available in order to waste no food.</p>

<h2>Ingredients</h2>

<ul>
<li>well-washed stone</li>
<li>kidney beans or fresh</li>
<li>pig's ear (blanched and sliced thin)</li>
<li>chouriço negro or firm type of blood sausage</li>
<li>mixed meat chouriço or mediterranean smoked sausage</li>
<li>pork belly, fatback or bacon</li>
<li>potatoes, cubed</li>
<li>onions, chopped</li>
<li>garlic cloves</li>
<li>bay leaf</li>
<li>cilantro/coriander, chopped</li>
</ul>

<h2>Directions</h2>

<ol>
<li>In a saucepan, boil the kidney beans with the pig's ear, sausages, pork belly, onions, garlic and bay leaf in some water and add a well-washed stone. Season with the olive oil and salt and pepper to taste.</li>
<li>If necessary, add more water while it’s boiling. </li>
<li>Once the meat is cooked, take it out and reserve, then add the diced potatoes and cilantro to the pot.</li>
<li>Let the potatoes cook on medium to high heat for about 30-35 minutes.</li>
<li>Once the potatoes are well cooked, you can remove the pot from the heat, add the previously chopped meat back in and stir it well.</li>
<li>Pour into bowls and serve.</li>
</ol>

<h2>Story</h2>

<blockquote>
  <p>A poor friar who was on a pilgrimage stopped in the village of Almeirim and knocked on the door of a house. He was too proud to beg for a bite to eat, so instead, he requested a large pot in which he could make “a delicious and filling…….stone soup”. With arched eyebrows and curious glances, the family invited him into their home and set up a large pot over flickering flames and filled with water. Slowly walking up to the ironclad cauldron, the friar reached into his deep pocket to produce a smooth and well-cleaned stone that he promptly dropped into the boiling water. A little while later he tasted the soup and said that it needed a touch of seasoning. So the wife brought him some salt to add, to which he suggested that maybe a little bit of chouriço (sausage), or pork belly, would be better. Graciously, she obliged and dropped several thick slices into the pot. Then, the friar asked if she might not have a little something to enrich the soup, such as potatoes or beans from a previous meal. With a broad smile, she agreed, and added a healthy portion into the bubbling water. This banter continued back and forth between the family and the friar before he finally announced that he had indeed made a very delicious and filling soup. When the soup was done, the friar fished the stone out of the pot, washed and dried it off, and plopped it back in his pocket for the next time.
  - According to the people of Almeirim</p>
</blockquote>

<h2>Contribution</h2>

<ul>
<li>Artur Mancha -- <a href="https://pleroma.pt/@lisbonjoker">Pleroma</a></li>
</ul>

<p>;tags: portuguese soup pork</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title type="text">Arroz Chaufa</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://based.cooking/arroz-chaufa.html"/>
<id>https://based.cooking/arroz-chaufa.html</id>
<published>2021-03-20T16:04:10Z</published>
<updated>2021-03-20T16:04:10Z</updated>
<author><name>Joshix</name></author>
<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Arroz Chaufa</h1>

<p>Peruvian-chinese dish, Easy to cook just add and mix everything.</p>

<p><img src="pix/arroz_chaufa-2.webp" alt="Arroz Chaufa" /></p>

<ul>
<li>⏲️ Prep time: 40 min</li>
<li>🍳Cook time: 10 min</li>
<li>🍽️ Servings: 4</li>
</ul>

<h2>Ingredients</h2>

<ul>
<li>Rice</li>
<li>Salt</li>
<li>Bell Pepper</li>
<li>Chicken</li>
<li>Eggs</li>
<li>Soy Sauce</li>
<li>Welsh Onion</li>
</ul>

<p><img src="pix/arroz_chaufa-1.webp" alt="Ingredients" /></p>

<h2>Directions</h2>

<ol>
<li>Cut the chicken into pieces and fry it (don't forget the salt).</li>
<li>Cook scrambled eggs (don't forget the salt).</li>
<li>Cook the rice (if it is yesterday's rice better, preferably without salt).</li>
<li>Cut the welsh onion and bell pepper into small squares.</li>
<li>Mix everything over low heat, adding soy sauce.</li>
<li>Optional: add beacon, sesame oil.</li>
<li>(Everything is salty, you can reduce it with just a teaspoon of sugar, especially if you cook the rice with salt.)</li>
</ol>

<h2>Contribution</h2>

<ul>
<li>Andy Rufasto</li>
<li><a href="https://keyoxide.org/0A3D7C5B8C2499A8BEBCE72869D2E5C413569DA2"><img src="https://img.shields.io/badge/Contact-andy@andyrufasto.cf-succes?style=social&amp;logo=GNU-Privacy-Guard" alt="" /></a></li>
</ul>

<p>;tags: peruvian chinese rice</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title type="text">Baked Salmon</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://based.cooking/baked-salmon.html"/>
<id>https://based.cooking/baked-salmon.html</id>
<published>2021-03-20T16:04:10Z</published>
<updated>2021-03-20T16:04:10Z</updated>
<author><name>Joshix</name></author>
<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Baked Salmon</h1>

<p>Simple method for making a good serving of salmon. Goes well with just about anything.</p>

<ul>
<li>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min</li>
<li>🍳Cook time: 19 min</li>
</ul>

<h2>Ingredients</h2>

<ul>
<li>Salmon Steaks</li>
<li>Red Pepper Flakes</li>
<li>Lemon Juice</li>
<li>Butter</li>
<li>Cooking oil / spray</li>
<li>Aluminum Foil</li>
</ul>

<h2>Directions</h2>

<ol>
<li>Season salmon with salt, black pepper, and red pepper to taste. </li>
<li>Spray or rub in cooking oil on aluminum foil and place on cookie sheet or in baking pan.</li>
<li>Squeeze lemon juice and place a teaspoon of butter on each salmon steak.</li>
<li>Bake at 400°F / 200°C for 19 mins.</li>
</ol>

<h2>Contribution</h2>

<ul>
<li>Carl Zimmerman -- <a href="https://codingwithcarl.com">website</a></li>
</ul>

<p>;tags: basic fish</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title type="text">Banana Bread</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://based.cooking/banana-bread.html"/>
<id>https://based.cooking/banana-bread.html</id>
<published>2021-03-20T16:04:10Z</published>
<updated>2021-03-20T16:04:10Z</updated>
<author><name>Joshix</name></author>
<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Banana Bread</h1>

<p>Not too sweet. Great for when you have friends over for tea.</p>

<h2>Ingredients</h2>

<ul>
<li>2 cups all purpose flour</li>
<li>1 1/2 teaspoon baking powder</li>
<li>1/2 teaspoon baking soda</li>
<li>Spices:
<ul>
<li>1 teaspoon cinnamon</li>
<li>1/4 teaspoon nutmeg</li>
<li>1/4 teaspoon ginger</li>
</ul></li>
<li>1/4 teaspoon salt</li>
<li>1 1/2 cups mashed bananas (this is around 4-5 bananas)</li>
<li>2 eggs</li>
<li>1 cup sugar (brown or white is fine)</li>
<li>1/2 cup butter or vegetable oil</li>
<li>1/4 cup crushed walnuts</li>
</ul>

<h2>Directions</h2>

<ol>
<li>Preheat oven to 350°F (175°C)</li>
<li>Mix the wet ingredients (eggs, bananas, oil, sugar) in one bowl.</li>
<li>Mix the dry ingredients (flour, baking soda/powder, spices, salt) in another
bowl.</li>
<li>Slowly add the wet to the dry while mixing.</li>
<li>Mix until dry bits of flour are gone.</li>
<li>Pour into lightly buttered or oiled loaf pan.</li>
<li>Bake for around an hour (it's definitely ready when a wooden skewer or
chopstick poked inside comes out clean).</li>
</ol>

<h2>Contribution</h2>

<ul>
<li>Martin Chrzanowski -- <a href="https://m-chrzan.xyz">website</a>, <a href="https://m-chrzan.xyz/crypto.html">donate</a></li>
</ul>

<p>;tags: bread dessert sweet</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title type="text">Banana Green Smoothie</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://based.cooking/banana-green-smoothie.html"/>
<id>https://based.cooking/banana-green-smoothie.html</id>
<published>2021-03-20T16:04:10Z</published>
<updated>2021-03-20T16:04:10Z</updated>
<author><name>Joshix</name></author>
<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Banana Green Smoothie</h1>

<h2>Ingredients</h2>

<ul>
<li>2 cups baby spinach leaves, or to taste</li>
<li>1 banana</li>
<li>1 carrot, peeled and cut into large chunks</li>
<li>3/4 cup plain fat-free Greek yogurt, or to taste</li>
<li>3/4 cup ice</li>
<li>2 tablespoons honey</li>
</ul>

<h2>Directions</h2>

<ol>
<li>Put spinach, banana, carrot, yogurt, ice, and honey in a blender; blend until smooth.</li>
</ol>

<h2>Contribution</h2>

<p>Front3ndNinja - <a href="https://github.com/Front3ndNinja">Website</a></p>

<p>;tags: drink sweet breakfast</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title type="text">Banana Muffins with Chocolate</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://based.cooking/banana-muffins-with-chocolate.html"/>
<id>https://based.cooking/banana-muffins-with-chocolate.html</id>
<published>2021-03-20T16:04:10Z</published>
<updated>2021-03-20T16:04:10Z</updated>
<author><name>Joshix</name></author>
<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Banana Muffins with Chocolate</h1>

<h2>Ingredients</h2>

<ul>
<li>3 bananas</li>
<li>100 g / ½ cups butter</li>
<li>150 g / ¾ cups sugar</li>
<li>2 eggs</li>
<li>1½ tsp. cooking powder</li>
<li>260 g / 2⅛ cups wheat flour</li>
<li>50 g / 1¾ oz dark chocolate</li>
<li>50 g / 1¾ oz milk chocolate</li>
<li>some vanilla sugar (optional)</li>
</ul>

<h2>Directions</h2>

<ol>
<li>Peel the bananas and mush them together.</li>
<li>Whip the two eggs and mix them with the sugar.</li>
<li>Melt the butter, cut the chocolate into smaller pieces, and whip the eggs.</li>
<li>Pour the butter into the bananas, then add the flour, then the cooking powder, the chocolate, the whipped eggs and sugar, and the optional vanilla sugar; stirring it all the time.</li>
<li>Pour the mass into your muffin dish.</li>
<li>Heat up the oven to 160 °C / 320 °F and bake the muffins for around 20-30 minutes in 170 °C / 340 °F.</li>
</ol>

<h2>Contribution</h2>

<ul>
<li>Łukasz Drukała - <a href="https://masflam.com">website</a>, <a href="https://masflam.com/#donate">donate</a></li>
</ul>

<p>;tags: dessert sweet snack cake</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title type="text">Banana Pancakes</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://based.cooking/banana-pancakes.html"/>
<id>https://based.cooking/banana-pancakes.html</id>
<published>2021-03-20T16:04:10Z</published>
<updated>2021-03-20T16:04:10Z</updated>
<author><name>Joshix</name></author>
<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Banana Pancakes</h1>

<ul>
<li>Prep time: 10 minutes</li>
<li>Cook time: 10 minutes</li>
<li>Serves: 4 people</li>
</ul>

<h2>Ingredients</h2>

<ul>
<li>1 cup flour (2.5 dl)</li>
<li>1 tablespoon sugar</li>
<li>2 teaspoon baking powder</li>
<li>1 cup milk (2.5 dl)</li>
<li>1 egg</li>
<li>2 very ripe bananas</li>
</ul>

<h2>Directions</h2>

<ol>
<li>Combine flour, sugar, baking powder and a little bit of salt in a large mixing bowl.</li>
<li>Whisk milk and egg into the flour mixture until no clumps remain in the resulting batter.</li>
<li>Add mashed bananas and mix well.</li>
<li>Add some butter to a medium warm frying pan.</li>
<li>Make smaller or bigger pancakes, up to you. Wait until tiny air bubbles form on top (2 to 5 minutes), turn and continue frying until the bottom is browned. Repeat.</li>
</ol>

<p>Either eat the pancakes as they get ready or put a plate in a preheated oven (low degree) to keep the ready pancakes warm.</p>

<h2>Contribution</h2>

<ul>
<li>Ricky Lindén - <a href="https://rickylinden.com">website</a>, <a href="https://rickylinden.com/donate.html">donate</a></li>
</ul>

<p>;tags: breakfast quick sweet cake</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title type="text">Beef Goulash</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://based.cooking/beef-goulash.html"/>
<id>https://based.cooking/beef-goulash.html</id>
<published>2021-03-20T16:04:10Z</published>
<updated>2021-03-20T16:04:10Z</updated>
<author><name>Joshix</name></author>
<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Beef Goulash</h1>

<p><img src="pix/beef-goulash.webp" alt="Beef Goulash" /></p>

<p>Although it takes some time to make - about 1hr 30 minutes, it is actually quite
easy to make, and it is a really hearty and delicious recipe, if I do say so
myself.</p>

<h2>Ingredients</h2>

<p>The ingredients here are for about 2-3 portions, depending on your appetite:</p>

<ul>
<li>500g beef</li>
<li>300-400g potatoes</li>
<li>1 carrot</li>
<li>1 medium onion</li>
<li>12 tablespoons tomato paste</li>
<li>500ml water</li>
<li>3-4 garlic cloves</li>
<li>3-4 bay leaves</li>
<li>Curcuma</li>
<li>Paprika</li>
<li>Oregano</li>
<li>Parsley</li>
<li>Caraway</li>
<li>Basil (optional)</li>
<li>Cilantro (optional)</li>
<li>2-3 champignon mushrooms (optional)</li>
</ul>

<h2>Instructions</h2>

<ol>
<li>Heat up the frying pan and add some oil.</li>
<li>Cut the potatoes into small pieces and fry them on the frying pan over
medium-heat, add some salt.</li>
<li>Chop the onion.</li>
<li>Cut the beef into small enough pieces and dust with flour.</li>
<li>After about 15 minutes of frying the potatoes, add the onions and beef to the
pan and fry for another 10-15 minutes, or until brown.</li>
<li>While the beef, potatoes and onions are frying, cut the carrot and mushrooms,
and chop the parsley and cilantro.</li>
<li>Once the beef is brown, add water to the pan, and add the rest of the
ingredients, including salt, black pepper and herbs/spices to taste.</li>
<li>Mix thoroughly, cover the pan with a lid and stew for about 60-80 minutes
over low-heat. While it is stewing, you can get back to doing some other
things, like watching memes.</li>
<li>Remove from stove, serve hot and enjoy with some beer or cider (or your
favorite beverage).</li>
</ol>

<p>Originally published at <a href="https://www.yaroslavps.com/food/beef-goulash/">https://www.yaroslavps.com/food/beef-goulash/</a></p>

<h2>Contribution</h2>

<ul>
<li>Yaroslav de la Peña Smirnov — <a href="https://www.yaroslavps.com/">website</a>, 
<a href="https://saucesource.cc/">other website</a>,
<a href="https://www.yaroslavps.com/donate">donate</a></li>
</ul>

<p>;tags: hungarian beef stew</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title type="text">Beef Jerky</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://based.cooking/beef-jerky.html"/>
<id>https://based.cooking/beef-jerky.html</id>
<published>2021-03-20T16:04:10Z</published>
<updated>2021-03-20T16:04:10Z</updated>
<author><name>Joshix</name></author>
<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Beef Jerky</h1>

<p>Beef Jerky is ideal for road trips and camping, as it will not perish as readily as fresh meat.
It is suitable not only as a snack but also as a meal.
This recipe for jerky is not heavily brined and flavored as commercial jerky is.</p>

<h2>Ingredients</h2>

<ul>
<li>¾ tsp. salt</li>
<li>¼ tsp. pepper</li>
<li>1 tbl. brown sugar</li>
<li>¼ tsp. garlic</li>
<li>2 tbl. Worcestershire sauce or Teriyaki sauce</li>
<li>¼ tsp. Liquid Smoke</li>
<li>1 Lb. (450 g) beef (flank or skirt steak is ideal)</li>
<li>Other common seasonings may include (¼ tsp. of) cayenne pepper, cheese powder, and/or white pepper</li>
</ul>

<h2>Directions</h2>

<ol>
<li>Mince or press garlic.</li>
<li>Mix all ingredients except beef to make brine.</li>
<li>Slice beef into ¼" (½ cm) thick strips. Small chunks, about ¾" (2 cm), of stewing beef may also be used. If possible, cut along the grain of the meat rather than across it. It may be easier to freeze the meat before attempting to cut it, as this will stop the meat pulling and deforming so easily.</li>
<li>Marinate meat in overnight, or at least for an hour or two.</li>
<li>Place meat on racks and dry in a food dehydrator at 145 °F (63 °C) for 6-8 hours. May be dried in a 150 °F (65 °C) oven with foil-covered racks. In oven, turn meat over 3-4 hours into drying time and reduce temperature to 130 °F (55 °C).</li>
<li>Meat should bend but not break when properly dried.</li>
</ol>

<h2>Note</h2>

<p>Other meats may be substituted instead of beef, but use caution.</p>

<h2>Contribution</h2>

<ul>
<li>Elias Howell -- <a href="https://snarf.top">website</a></li>
</ul>

<p>;tags: beef snack</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title type="text">Traditional beef or lamb stew</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://based.cooking/beef-stew.html"/>
<id>https://based.cooking/beef-stew.html</id>
<published>2021-03-20T16:04:10Z</published>
<updated>2021-03-20T16:04:10Z</updated>
<author><name>Joshix</name></author>
<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Traditional beef or lamb stew</h1>

<p>This is a recipe for a typical Irish stew. This is traditionally made with lamb since it's cheaper however, beef tastes a lot better and is more readily available in North America I've been told. This is good if you want to feed a family or if you just want to be lazy and eat the same thing for 2 or 3 days.</p>

<p>Serve with mashed potatoes.</p>

<h2>Ingredients</h2>

<ul>
<li>Lamb shoulder or beef chuck </li>
<li>Onion, celery, carrot and garlic</li>
<li>Thyme, rosemary and some bay leaves.</li>
<li>Beef or <a href="https://based.cooking/chicken-stock-bone-broth.html">chicken stock</a></li>
<li>(Optional) a bottle of stout or porter for some extra flavour.</li>
</ul>

<h2>Directions</h2>

<ol>
<li>Cut up the onion, carrot and celery into bite-sized chunks roughly the same size as the meat. The garlic can go in whole.</li>
<li>Brown the meat on all sides. Get a large pot with some oil and sear the edges of the meat. Do this in batches and try not to overcrowd the pot. Browning the meat on the outside will give it a much nicer texture when you go to eat this and <strong>should not be skipped for convenience</strong>.</li>
<li>Remove the meat and add in the vegetables. Adding some salt will help remove the moisture in the veg and will help deglaze the caramelised bits at the bottom of the pot.</li>
<li>(Optional) If you have a Guinness or some other stout add the meat back in an deglaze with about a third of the can. This will add some extra flavour. Wait until the alcohol has completely evaporated until you stir or continue.</li>
<li>Add back in the meat and add in the stock and herbs. Lower the heat and allow to simmer for about 2 - 2.5 hours.</li>
<li>After 2 hours the stew will be a bit thicker but probably still watery. The easiest thing to do is add some cut up potatoes for the last half hour. The starch will help thicken the stew considerably. Otherwise you can mix a teaspoon of flour with water in a cup and slowly add this to the stew while whisking.</li>
</ol>

<p>There you have it, an idiot-proof stew that should taste reasonably well. Besides browning the meat this is really just throwing stuff into a pot in a certain order. This is the kind of dish that tastes better the next day so it's ideal for making on a Sunday and eating for the next 2 or 3 days.</p>

<h2>Contribution</h2>

<ul>
<li>Eoin Coogan - <a href="https://eoincoogan.com">website</a>, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCehh50T6qtDpt_kEUF33GJw">youtube</a></li>
</ul>

<p>;tags: irish stew lamb beef</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title type="text">Beef Tips in Gravy on Sour Cream Mashed Potatoes</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://based.cooking/beef-tips.html"/>
<id>https://based.cooking/beef-tips.html</id>
<published>2021-03-20T16:04:10Z</published>
<updated>2021-03-20T16:04:10Z</updated>
<author><name>Joshix</name></author>
<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Beef Tips in Gravy on Sour Cream Mashed Potatoes</h1>

<p>Tender chunks of meat in a rich brown gravy poured over sour cream mashed potatoes, made in a pressure cooker. This recipe is a modification of the <a href="https://youtu.be/91gAm1hBaT4">Texas Cafe Classics Sirloin Tips Recipe</a> by Mark Rippetoe.</p>

<h2>Ingredients</h2>

<ul>
<li>Any lean, tough cut of meat (ex. round steak)</li>
<li>Unprocessed animal fat of some kind (ex. beef suet, mutton fat)</li>
<li>Potatoes</li>
<li>Sour cream</li>
<li>Butter</li>
<li>Milk</li>
<li>Shredded cheese of your choice</li>
<li>Small amount of flour</li>
<li>Beef bouillon (optional)</li>
<li>Red wine (optional)</li>
</ul>

<h2>Directions</h2>

<p><strong>Beef Tips in Gravy</strong></p>

<ol>
<li>Throw your pressure cooker with an open lid onto high heat or turn it onto saute mode if it's electric</li>
<li>Chop up the fat into very small, uniform cubes or strips and begin to saute it in the pressure cooker</li>
<li>Chop up your meat into medium, uniform cubes or strips and add it to the fat</li>
<li><em>Optional</em>: If you are not using red wine as a deglaze in step 7 or are not cooking a large amount (~2+ pounds/~1+ kg) of meat, you may want to add a teaspoon or so of beef bouillon into the pressure cooker to intensify the beef flavor of the gravy</li>
<li>Add a generous amount of salt and pepper to taste along with a tiny pinch of garlic powder and stir (be very conservative with the garlic powder)</li>
<li>Once the meat is sufficiently browned off and there is a nice glaze forming on the bottom of the cooker, deglaze the cooker using hot water or red wine (optional) for more flavor.</li>
<li>Put the top on your pressure cooker and allow the meat to cook for around 30 minutes on low heat while you prepare your mashed potatoes</li>
<li>After half an hour, vent your pressure cooker, remove the lid, and put the cooker back on low heat</li>
<li>Add a small amount of hot water until the liquid in the cooker is a bit more than the amount of gravy you want, then allow it to come to a boil</li>
<li>In a small bowl, mix up some flour with warm water to the consistency of a very runny batter</li>
<li>Very slowly begin adding flour water into the pot while constantly stirring until the gravy thickens and reaches the consistency you desire (it's very easy to overthicken the gravy here, don't overdo it!)</li>
<li>Turn off the heat and plate on top of your sour cream mashed potatoes, shown below</li>
</ol>

<p><strong>Sour Cream Mashed Potatoes</strong></p>

<ol>
<li>Peel and dice up your potatoes</li>
<li>Boil them on medium heat in a pot of slightly salty water until they begin to fall apart when poked with a fork</li>
<li>Turn off the heat and pour off the water</li>
<li>Mash up the potatoes to the chunkiness you desire</li>
<li>While the potatoes are still warm, add a generous amount of butter and shredded cheese and stir</li>
<li>Add a very small amount of milk and stir (be conservative here, the sour cream will provide most of the softness of the mash)</li>
<li>Begin adding sour cream and thoroughly mixing until the mash reaches your desired consistency</li>
<li>Plate under your beef tips in gravy</li>
</ol>

<h2>Contributors</h2>

<ul>
<li><strong>Batu Cam</strong> -- Transcribed recipe from Mark Rippetoe's video with moderate to significant modifications based on experience -- Monero (XMR) to help me save for an unazoomer cabin: <code>85eZ4uVd4gkiCsQEeDnsQG9pUbDzdi1r1VSJ9hK5Sx7hKsFZjvmqtWV7gU1ysWUR32jhWutBRGUUq8VAJNUfin9wBCCuTdg</code></li>
<li><strong>Mark Rippetoe</strong> -- Original recipe author, creator of starting strength, and pink nationalist -- <a href="https://startingstrength.com">Website</a></li>
</ul>

<p>;tags: american beef potato</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title type="text">Bloody Mary Mix</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://based.cooking/bloody-mary-mix.html"/>
<id>https://based.cooking/bloody-mary-mix.html</id>
<published>2021-03-20T16:04:10Z</published>
<updated>2021-03-20T16:04:10Z</updated>
<author><name>Joshix</name></author>
<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Bloody Mary Mix</h1>

<ul>
<li>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min</li>
<li>🍳Cook time: 5 min</li>
<li>🍽️ Servings: 8</li>
</ul>

<h2>Ingredients</h2>

<ul>
<li>1 (46 fluid ounce) bottle tomato-vegetable juice cocktail</li>
<li>1 fruit, without seeds lemons, juiced</li>
<li>1 teaspoon brown sugar</li>
<li>1 tablespoon steak sauce</li>
<li>1 tablespoon Worcestershire sauce</li>
<li>1 teaspoon prepared horseradish</li>
<li>1 teaspoon hot pepper sauce</li>
<li>1/2 teaspoon celery salt</li>
</ul>

<h2>Directions</h2>

<ol>
<li>In a large pitcher, combine juice cocktail, lemon juice and brown sugar. Season with Worcestershire sauce, horseradish, hot sauce and celery salt. Cover, and refrigerate 8 to 12 hours to allow flavors to meld.</li>
</ol>

<h2>Contribution</h2>

<p>Front3ndNinja - <a href="https://github.com/Front3ndNinja">Website</a></p>

<p>;tags: drink sweet breakfast</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title type="text">Bolinhos de Coco</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://based.cooking/bolinhos-de-coco.html"/>
<id>https://based.cooking/bolinhos-de-coco.html</id>
<published>2021-03-20T16:04:10Z</published>
<updated>2021-03-20T16:04:10Z</updated>
<author><name>Joshix</name></author>
<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Bolinhos de Coco</h1>

<p>This is a Portuguese dish that translates to "coconut cupcakes," though there are probably lots of equivalent dishes from other cultures.
Its simplicity and short preparation time make it perfect for a snack or dessert.</p>

<ul>
<li>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min</li>
<li>🍳Cook time: 10 min</li>
</ul>

<h2>Ingredients</h2>

<ul>
<li>300 g coconut</li>
<li>150 g sugar</li>
<li>3 egg yolks</li>
<li>1 whole egg</li>
<li>Powdered sugar (optional)</li>
</ul>

<h2>Directions</h2>

<ol>
<li>Mix the non-optional ingredients in a medium bowl.</li>
<li>Scoop tablespoons of the batter into a cookie sheet or cupcake pan.</li>
<li>Cook for around 10 minutes or until slightly brown on top.</li>
<li>Top with powdered sugar if desired.</li>
<li>Let cool and enjoy!</li>
</ol>

<h2>Contribution</h2>

<ul>
<li>A family recipe (not mine)</li>
<li>Submitted by Mealwhiles</li>
</ul>

<p>;tags: portuguese quick sweet snack dessert</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title type="text">Basic Bread Recipe</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://based.cooking/bread.html"/>
<id>https://based.cooking/bread.html</id>
<published>2021-03-20T16:04:10Z</published>
<updated>2021-03-20T16:04:10Z</updated>
<author><name>Joshix</name></author>
<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Basic Bread Recipe</h1>

<p>This is a recipe for a basic loaf of bread. The dough itself can be used however. I've made buns, rolls, and whole bread loafs using this same exact dough every time without a problem. Eat within 3 days as it will probably be going stale around then (as bread without preservatives and other junk should).</p>

<h2>Ingredients</h2>

<ul>
<li>1 1/2 cups warm water</li>
<li>2 and 1/4 teaspoons Active Dry Yeast</li>
<li>1 Tsp sugar</li>
<li>2 Tbsp  maple syrup, agave, or honey</li>
<li>1/2 Tbsp salt</li>
<li>3 3/4 cups Unbleached All-Purpose Flour (plus more for rolling / dusting)</li>
</ul>

<h2>Instructions</h2>

<ol>
<li>Proof the yeast. To do this warm 1/4 cup water to about bath water heat (110 degrees F, 43 degrees C) add active dry yeast and 1 Tsp sugar. Let sit for about 10 minutes, mixture should at least be doubled in size after waiting.</li>
<li>Combine rest of water, yeast mixture, maple syrup (or other sweetener), salt, and flour in a large mixing bowl and stir. The result will be a sticky, rough dough. Use a spoon to stir until well combined and when it can no longer do the job, knead and turn it in the bowl with your hands.</li>
<li>Lift the dough out and lightly grease the bowl with nonstick spray or olive oil. Cover and let rise for 2 hours at room temperature.</li>
<li>Transfer dough to a lightly floured work surface and knead until dough is elastic. Rule of thumb is 10 minutes of kneading.</li>
<li>Place seam-side down in a lightly greased loaf pan or baking sheet. Loosely cover with plastic wrap and let rest for 45-60 minutes.</li>
<li>Preheat oven to 425 degrees F (218 C)* toward the end of the dough resting time and place a metal pan (NOT glass, Pyrex, or ceramic) on the lowest oven rack. Also have 1 cup of hot water ready.</li>
<li>When the oven is preheated, slash the bread 2 or 3 times with a knife, making a cut about ½-inch deep.</li>
<li>Place in oven on middle rack. Then carefully pour hot water into the shallow pan on the rack beneath. Expect it to bubble and steam; then close oven door quickly.</li>
<li>Bake the bread for 26 to 35 minutes, or until deep golden brown and risen. Tapping the top of the loaf should produce a hollow sound.</li>
<li>Remove the bread from the oven and let rest in the pan for 5 minutes. Then carefully remove from pan and transfer to a cooling rack to cool. Let it cool completely before slicing for best results (otherwise it can be doughy in the middle).</li>
<li>Store leftovers in a plastic bag at room temperature for up to a few days. Transfer to freezer for longer term storage.</li>
</ol>

<h2>Notes</h2>

<ul>
<li>Instant yeast is not recommended as you can't easily tell if the bread will come to life.</li>
<li>For whole wheat version use 2 cups of whole wheat bread and 1 and 3/4 cup unbleached all purpose flour.</li>
<li>Add sunflower seeds and/or rolled oats for extra flavor/grains.</li>
<li>For buns or rolls divide dough into smaller pieces before second rest. Shape them and then let the dough rest. Recommended lowering oven temperature to 350 F and not using water as those will result in a hard crust and potentially dry interior.</li>
</ul>

<h2>Contribution</h2>

<p>Alex Selimov - <a href="https://alexselimov.xyz">Website</a></p>

<p>;tags: basic bread</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title type="text">Breton Crêpes (Breton Galettes)</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://based.cooking/breton-crepes.html"/>
<id>https://based.cooking/breton-crepes.html</id>
<published>2021-03-20T16:04:10Z</published>
<updated>2021-03-20T16:04:10Z</updated>
<author><name>Joshix</name></author>
<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Breton Crêpes (Breton Galettes)</h1>

<p>Buckwheat crêpes eaten as dishes, traditionaly garnished with ham, eggs and cheese (galette complète).</p>

<p>~15/20 galettes.</p>

<h2>Ingredients</h2>

<ul>
<li>500g buckwheat flour</li>
<li>1 egg</li>
<li>70cl water</li>
</ul>

<h2>Directions</h2>

<ol>
<li>Mix flour, salt, egg and water. (In this order to avoid dry flour)</li>
<li>Let it rest one hour at room temperature.</li>
<li>Cook the galette on a crepe-maker or a big flat pan.</li>
<li>When garnishing, heat the galette again with a bit of salted butter.</li>
</ol>

<p>Always keep the crepe-maker's T stick in water while cooking so the dough doesn't dry on it.
It will then be easier to spread the dough.</p>

<h3>Contributor</h3>

<ul>
<li>Aeredren - <a href="https://github.com/Aeredren">GitHub</a></li>
</ul>

<p>;tags: french</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title type="text">Brigadeiro</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://based.cooking/brigadeiro.html"/>
<id>https://based.cooking/brigadeiro.html</id>
<published>2021-03-20T16:04:10Z</published>
<updated>2021-03-20T16:04:10Z</updated>
<author><name>Joshix</name></author>
<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Brigadeiro</h1>

<p>A very traditional brazilian dessert that is present in every brazilian birthday party! Delicious and super easy to make.</p>

<h2>Ingredients:</h2>

<ul>
<li>One can of condensed milk.</li>
<li>Three or four spoons of chocolate powder or cocoa powder.</li>
<li>One spoon of butter (actual butter pls, no margerine!)</li>
</ul>

<h2>Instructions:</h2>

<ol>
<li>Add all the ingredients into a pan</li>
<li>Put it under low heat and stir it (preferably with a wooden spoon) it until it starts sticking to the bottom of the pan</li>
<li>Remove it from the pan and eat it with a spoon or wait for it to cool down and roll it into small balls!</li>
</ol>

<h2>Closing remarks:</h2>

<p>Depending on how much brigadeiro you want to do, you'll have to add more or less of each ingredient, so be creative! Be careful with the chocolate powder, you definitely do not want to add too much of it!</p>

<h2>Contribution</h2>

<p>https://github.com/cabinetto</p>

<p>;tags: dessert quick </p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title type="text">Broiled Trevally</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://based.cooking/broiled-trevally.html"/>
<id>https://based.cooking/broiled-trevally.html</id>
<published>2021-03-20T16:04:10Z</published>
<updated>2021-03-20T16:04:10Z</updated>
<author><name>Joshix</name></author>
<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Broiled Trevally</h1>

<p>Well, it's actually a <em>giant</em> trevally, and if you have seen one, that fish looks ugly.
So here's a recipe to make it look---and taste!---more appealing.</p>

<h2>Ingredients</h2>

<ul>
<li>giant trevally</li>
<li>eggplants</li>
<li>squash (or zucchini)</li>
<li>carrots</li>
<li>onion</li>
<li>garlic</li>
<li>ginger</li>
<li>tomatoes</li>
<li>bay leaf</li>
<li>olive oil</li>
<li>thyme</li>
<li>basil</li>
<li>butter</li>
</ul>

<h2>Directions</h2>

<ol>
<li>Dice carrots, eggplant, squash, tomatoes and onions. Place these on a pan.</li>
<li>Put basil, thyme, bay leaf, salt, and pepper on each of the fish's side. Place the fish above the veggies.</li>
<li>Crush garlic and ginger (with <a href="mortar-and-pestle.html">mortar and pestle, of course</a>) and place this in and around the fish.</li>
<li>Give it all a good splash of olive oil.</li>
<li>Cover the pan and set to medium-low fire, until everything looks cooked.</li>
<li>Flip the fish on the other side, just to make sure that it's properly cooked.</li>
<li>Check the doneness of the squash: if it's cooked, everything is.</li>
<li>Let everything set for 5 mins. before serving.</li>
</ol>

<h2>Contribution</h2>

<ul>
<li>O.Q. Olarte <a href="https://oqolarte.github.io">website</a>, <a href="https://oqolarte.github.io/support">donate</a></li>
</ul>

<p>;tags: fish</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title type="text">Butter Chicken Masala Curry</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://based.cooking/butter-chicken-masala.html"/>
<id>https://based.cooking/butter-chicken-masala.html</id>
<published>2021-03-20T16:04:10Z</published>
<updated>2021-03-20T16:04:10Z</updated>
<author><name>Joshix</name></author>
<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Butter Chicken Masala Curry</h1>

<p>Butter chicken Masala is one of India's most popular chicken recipes, a mild curry with a tomato-onion-cream base and boneless chicken pieces cooked in it to perfection.</p>

<ul>
<li>Prep time: 30 min</li>
<li>Cook time: 30 min</li>
<li>Servings: 2</li>
</ul>

<h2>Ingredients</h2>

<ul>
<li>Boneless Chicken 1/2lb, cubed</li>
<li>Butter Melted 2 tbsp</li>
<li>Onions 2 medium-sized, minced</li>
<li>Tomato 2 medium-sized, pureed</li>
<li>Oil 2 tbsp</li>
<li>Lemon juice 1 tbsp</li>
<li>Garlic cloves 3, minced/crushed</li>
<li>Ginger 1tbsp, minced/paste</li>
<li>Garam Masala/Chicken Masala 1 tbsp</li>
<li>Cream 4tbsp (or cashew paste)</li>
<li>Chilli Powder 1 tbsp</li>
<li>Turmeric powder 1/4 tbsp</li>
<li>Crushed fenugreek leaves 1/4 tbsp</li>
<li>1 small bunch of coriander leaves / cilantro, for ganish</li>
</ul>

<h2>Directions</h2>

<ol>
<li>In a bowl, mix chicken with salt, pepper, 1/2 tbsp ginger-garlic paste, 1/2 tbsp chili powder, turmeric powder, and lemon juice for the chicken marinade; let marinate for an hour.</li>
<li>Roast the marinated chicken in an oven at medium temperature for 5 to 10 minutes. The chicken should be three-fourths done.</li>
<li>Heat butter in a pan. Fry the onions until it turns translucent.</li>
<li>Add garlic-ginger and sauté for a minute, then add garam masala. Cook for a few seconds making sure not to burn the paste.</li>
<li>Add tomato puree, salt, and chili powder. Let simmer for about 5 minutes, occasionally stirring until sauce thickens and becomes a deep brown-red color.</li>
<li>Add the marinated chicken, butter, fresh cream, the crushed fenugreek leaves, and sliced green chilies. Cook for an additional 5 to 10 min until the chicken is cooked.</li>
<li>Adjust salt, garnish with the coriander leaves. Serve over rice or naan.</li>
</ol>

<h2>Contribution</h2>

<ul>
<li>Nihar Samantaray - <a href="https://nihars.com">website</a>, <a href="mailto:i@nihars.com">contact</a></li>
</ul>

<p>;tags: indian curry chicken</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
</feed>
